Finding Aid for John C. Floyd Papers, 1960-1978
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
John C. Floyd Papers 1960-1978
Floyd, John C., 1927-
1.5 linear ft.
921123 Aa 2
Professor of internal medicine at the University of Michigan. Laboratory workbooks on diabetology and endocrinology from 1960 to 1978.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was the gift of John C. Floyd (Donor no. 7876 ) and came to the library in November 1990.
The collection is open to research.
John C. Floyd was born on July 3, 1927 in Olla, Louisiana. He received his undergraduate degree in chemistry from Louisiana State University in 1949. He also received his M.D. from the same university in 1954. In 1958, John C. Floyd came to the University of Michigan Medical School as an instructor in internal medicine. From 1959 until 1960, he was instructor of internal medicine at Louisiana State University School of Medicine. In 1960 Floyd returned to the University of Michigan as assistant professor of internal medicine. From 1964 to 1970 he was an associate professor at the medical school. Floyd has been a professor of internal medicine at the University of Michigan since 1970. Additionally, Floyd served as director of the Diabetes Care Unit at the University of Michigan Medical School from 1977 to 1986.
John C. Floyd's major areas of research are diabetology and endocrinology. He is a member of the American Diabetes Association serving on the board of directors from 1974 to 1980. He has written numerous articles. For a complete listing of published articles and professional activities please consult the very inclusive curriculum vitae in folder 1, box 1.
The collection consists primarily of laboratory workbooks of various experiments conducted between 1960 and 1978. The workbooks concern such subjects as the iodination of insulin, the immunization of guinea pigs, and the immuno assay of insulin.
A second set of workbooks concern the growth hormone. Unfortunately workbooks 4-8 are missing from this set. The third sequence of workbooks relate to insulin radioiodination.
Additionally, the collection includes experimental notes on glucagon radioiodination and gastrin iodination. The last workbook consists of quality control estimates for the HPP assay. There is also one folder of unidentified results from 1962. For a fuller understanding of the results of the assays, please consult the curriculum vitae for published articles on these topics.
Subjects:
Endocrinology.; Floyd, John C., 1927-; University of Michigan. Dept. of Internal Medicine.; University of Michigan--Faculty.; University of Michigan. Medical school.
- Biographical
  - Curriculum Vitae (Box 1)
- Laboratory workbooks
  - Experiments re Insulin/Immuno Assay Data, 1960-1963, 6 volumes (Box 1)
  - Experiments re Insulin Iodination Data, 1962-1965, 4 volumes (Box 1)
  - Experiments re Growth Hormone, 1963-1967, 4 volumes (Box 1)
  - Experiments re Insulin Radioiodination, 1967-1968, 2 volumes (Box 2)
  - Experiments re Glucagon Radioiodinations, 1967-1970 (Box 2)
  - Experiments re Gastrin Iodinations, 1972 (Box 2)
  - Experiments re Quality Control/HPP Assays, 1975-1978 (Box 2)
  - Unlabeled experimental data, 1962 (Box 2)